Guide to the Walter Freeman and James Watts collection, 1918-1988 MS0803.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Publications - General, 1928-1975; MS0803 Series 3; 1 Linear foot (Box 45, Box 44, Box 46)
  - Publications General M: Marks, I.M. Modified Leucotomy in Severe Agoraphobia (1966); Mueller, Christian Gottlieb Burckhardt, The Father of Topectomy (1960); Meyer, A. Reflections on the Rationale of Prefrontal Leucotomy and Related Operations (1958); Miller, A. The Lobotomy Patient, A Decade Later (1967); Mueller, Edward Adjustment Levels Following Transorbital Lobotomy (1954); et al, 1928-1967 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Publications General N: Negrin, Juan Brain Surgery in Mental Illness(1955); Nelson, Erland Pathological Effects of Ultrasound on the Human Brain (1959); et al, 1954-1955 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Publications General O-P: Oltman, Long Term Results of Prefrontal Lobotomy in Schizophrenic Patients (1961); Powell, Charles An Evaluation of Results in 71 Transorbital Lobotomy Cases Five Years Postoperative (1955); Pool, Lawrence Psychosurgery in Older People (1954); Polonio, Pedro Involutional Schizophrenia (1954); et al, 1954-1966 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Publications General S: Scoville, William Late Results of Orbital Undercutting (1960); Schmidt, Arnold Rehabilitation and Ethical Values of Lobotomized Patients (1955); Sargant, Willam The Present Indications for Leucotomy (1962); Sagebiel, James Regressive Convulsive Therapy and Lobotomy in the Treatment of Mental Disorders (1961); Scoville, W.B. The Limbic Lobe in Man (1954); et al, 1951-1964 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Publications General T-Z: Thorpe, F.T. Emotional Breakdowns in the Elderly (1959); Tucker, Walter Results of Lobotomy (1961); Tow, P. Macdonald Orbital Leucotomy (1953), Zlotlow, Moses Autoerotic and Homoerotic Manifestations in Hospitalized Male Postlobotomy Patients (1959); et al, 1948-1966 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Affiliation agreement, GW and Washington Hospital Center, 1966-1967 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Bibliographic index cards summarizing articles written by researchers on the subject of psychosurgery, 1942-1967 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    arranged alphabetically
- George Washington University Hospital, 1949-1968; MS0803 Series 4; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 47, Box 49, Box 48)
  This series contains materials dealing with Watts' involvement with the medical school and hospital, including the residency training program and statistics on neurological surgery. This material dates from 1949-68.
  - American Board of Neurological Surgery correspondence, reports, 1964-1968 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - American Board of Neurological Surgery exam questions, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Children's Hospital, 1954 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with American Board of Neurological Surgery, 1967-1969 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - D.C. General Hospital statistics, 1954 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - D.C. General Hospital statistics, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Evaluation of Veterans Administration residency programs, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Gallinger Hospital, 1948-1951 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Helpful hints on neurological surgery board exams for residents, 1960 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Hospital malpractice claims, 1958 ca. (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Memos, schedules, 1940-1964 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Neurobiology course, 1976 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Neurological residency, 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Neurological surgery data and worksheets, 1954 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Neurological residents schedule of rotation, 1968-1969 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Neurosurgery Training examination, 12/10/1966 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Physiologic Principles in the Management of Head Injuries, GW Postgraduate program, 1956 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Residency data from Washington Hospital Center, 1959 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Residency training at Children's Hospital, 1949-1951 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Residency training program, 1950-1962 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Residency training program, 1951-1952 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Residency training program, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Residency training program, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Residency training program, 1953-1961 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Residency training program, 1954-1957 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Residency training program, 1955-1956 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Residency training program, 1954-1960 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Residency training program, 1961-1963 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Residency training program, 1961-1966 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Rotation of residents, 1968-1969 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Statistics AMA, 1963-1964 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Statistics for residents, 1957-1960 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Statistics on neurological surgery, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Statistics on neurological surgery, 1960-1961 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Statistics on neurological surgery, 1957-1963 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Statistics on neurological surgery, 1967-1968 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Statistics on neurological surgery, for GW affiliated hospitals, 1957-1966 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Statistics on procedures and examinations, 1960-1961 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Statistics on the residency program for American Medical Association, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Statistics on the residency program for American Medical Association, 1967-1968 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Surgery for Pain Relief, GW Postgraduate Program, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Veterans Administration Hospital, 1966 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Washington Hospital Center residency training, 1965-1966 (Box 49, Folder 8)
- Patient Records, ca.1940-ca.1970; MS0803 Series 5; 51 Linear feet (Box 77, Box 29 E, Box 76, Box 29 D, Box 75, Box 31 C, Box 74, Box 31 D, Box 29 A, Box 28 D, Box 79, Box 29 C, Box 78, Box 29 B, Box 28 A, Box 30 A, Box 28 C, Box 28 B, Box 73, Box 30 D, Box 72, Box 30 B, Box 30 C, Box 89, Box 42, Box 45, Box 44, Box 47, Box 46, Box 49, Box 48, Box 70, Box 69, Box 62A, Box 68, Box 71, Box 41, Box 40, Box 38, Box 39, Box 35, Box 25, Box 26, Box 21, Box 22, Box 36, Box 37, Box 27, Box 24, Box 17, Box 20, Box 19, Box 23, Box 4, Box 18, Box 15, Box 16, Box 6, Box 5, Box 1A, Box 3, Box 10, Box 9, Box 8, Box 7, Box 13, Box 11, Box 12, Box 62B, Box 62C, Box 33 C, Box 33 B, Box 31 B, Box 31 A, Box 32 B, Box 32 A, Box 33 A, Box 32 C, Box 34 C, Box 34 A, Box 34 B, Box 85, Box 86, Box 81, Box 84, Box 87, Box 88, Box 82, Box 83, Box 1B)
  Please note: this series is unprocessed and is restricted. Please see staff for assistance.